hey
嘿
welcome to part two of getting to know
欢迎收看《了解》第二部分
filmic
电影
i hope you've watched the part 1 of this
我希望你已经看过这篇文章的第一部分了
series where we pondered about
我们思考过的系列节目
photography and the whole concept of
摄影和整个概念
filmic what it's for and what it does
电影：它的用途和用途
otherwise this might feel like a baptism
否则 这可能会让人感觉像是在洗礼
by fire
被火烧死
let's not waste any time and let's jump
我们不要浪费时间了 我们跳吧
right in so today i'm going to be mainly
所以今天我将主要是
working on this inside and outside
从里到外都在努力
capture
捕获
next time
下次
this ultimate test of my abilities in
这是对我能力的终极考验
using filmic rgb module
使用胶片RGB模块
two photos that would normally be
两张通常会是
discarded if it wasn't for awesome tools
如果不是因为很棒的工具 就会被丢弃
we have today
我们今天有
we've dealt with a blown out sky in
我们已经处理了一场被吹散的天空
another video you can find it in the
另一个视频 你可以在
cards at the top right corner or in the
卡片在右上角或在
video description
视频描述
hence today we'll be looking at a few
因此 今天我们将关注几个
different examples
不同的例子
we'll start with the easier one
我们将从更简单的开始
first let's move to darkroom and let's
首先 让我们移到暗室 让我们
evaluate the level of brokenness
评估破损程度
let's check what's clipped at the sensor
让我们来看看传感器上夹了什么
and how much painting we'll have to do
以及我们要画多少画
and how much salvaging we should attempt
以及我们应该尝试多少打捞
looks pretty bad
看起来很糟糕
but nothing we can't fake fix
但没有什么是我们无法伪装修复的
okay let's start with a quick
好的 让我们从一个简短的开始
perspective adjustment
视角调整
type in perspective turn that on
以透视模式输入打开该选项
and click on all the automatic buttons
然后点击所有的自动按钮
this one scans the image for straight
这个可以扫描图像中的直线条
lines
线条
and that one corrects it vertically
而那一个垂直地纠正它
i'll close that and that looks much
我要把它合上 那看起来很多
nicer we're no longer feeling like ants
更好的是 我们不再感觉自己像蚂蚁
next up i'll adjust the temperature a
接下来我要把温度调到
little bit
一点点
as i can feel the photo is slightly
我能感觉到这张照片有点
bluish
略带蓝色
especially at the bottom here
尤其是在这里的底部
i'll just increase this
我只需要增加这个
until we're happy
直到我们开心为止
okay that looks about right
好的 看起来差不多对了
let's use the color assessment mode
让我们使用颜色评估模式
okay i'm pretty happy with that it's a
好的 我很高兴这是一个
bit on the warmer side but it was a
有点偏暖 但这是一种
really warm day
很暖和的一天
so i might want to convey that with my
所以我可能想用我的
image
图像
next up i'll adjust the exposure
下一步我会调整曝光
just a tiny bit
只有一点点
i feel like the image is a bit too
我觉得这个形象有点太过了
bright
明亮
knowing that this is a shadow area
知道这是一个阴影区
away from the sun
远离太阳
i might want to make it
我可能会想去的
a little bit darker
颜色稍微暗一点
remember that by setting the exposure
请记住 通过设置曝光
we're also picking where our neutral
我们还选择了我们的中立者
gray is going to be
格雷将会成为
now we can open filmic
现在我们可以打开电影
something that will actually fix some of
一些实际上可以修复一些问题的东西
the issues with the photo
这张照片的问题
i'm going to be using filmic v6 which is
我将使用电影V6 这是
going to reach the mainstream dark table
要进入主流的暗桌
pretty soon
很快就会
just so the video doesn't become
这样视频就不会变成
obsolete a weekend
使周末不复存在
i will set the preserved chrominance to
我会将保留的色度设置为
know for this video this might ruin our
我知道这个视频可能会毁了我们的
rgb ratios
RGB比率
but it's usually less noticeable than
但它通常不像
the artifacts that the other
他者的神器
preservation methods create that's my
保存方法创造了这是我的
experience at least right onto filmic
体验至少是在电影上
i'm going to use that auto-tune levels
我要用这个自动调节音量
which did a pretty good job
它做得很好
i would like to adjust the contrast just
我想把对比度调一下
a little bit
有一点
notice how this straight line rotates
注意这条直线是如何旋转的
around this orange dot which is our
围绕着这个橙色的点 这是我们的
neutral gray point
中性灰点
that we sort of set in the exposure
我们在曝光中设定的
module i'll move the slider to the right
模块我会将滑块移到右侧
and watch the straight line rotate
看着这条直线旋转
okay that's a bit too much i'll dial it
好的 有点太贵了 我要拨一下
back a bit
后退一点
that looks about right
看起来差不多对了
reduce the latitude a bit
把纬度降低一点
so we get some nicer transitions
所以我们得到了一些更好的过渡
okay i'm pretty happy with that
好的 我对此很满意
now we can switch to reconstruct tab
现在 我们可以切换到重建选项卡
first we need to select the areas
首先 我们需要选择区域
that we want to reconstruct we can do
我们想要重建我们可以做到的事情
that by enabling the mask preview
通过启用蒙版预览
right now nothing is selected so the
当前未选择任何内容 因此
reconstruct tab is basically disabled
重建选项卡基本上处于禁用状态
i will start walking back the threshold
我会开始走回门槛
slider
滑块
until we get white where there was
直到我们在原来的地方变白
significant overexposure
严重过度暴露
okay
好吧
i think it's
我想这是
right about here then using the
就在这里 然后使用
transition slider i can sort of feather
过渡滑块我可以像羽毛一样
my selection usually adjusting the
我的选择通常会调整
transition until i can vaguely see the
过渡 直到我可以隐约看到
rest of the image works best from my
图像的其余部分在我的
experience
体验
like that
就像这样
okay we can disable the mask
好的 我们可以禁用面具
that got rid of
去掉了
a little bit of pink we had before which
在此之前我们有一点粉色
means we're doing something right
意味着我们在做正确的事情
now we have these three sliders that
现在我们有这三个滑块
will help me hide my mistake of
会帮我隐藏我的错误
overexposure
过度曝光
i'll zoom in just a little bit so we can
我会稍微放大一点 这样我们就可以
see better
看得更清楚
the first slider is structure versus
第一个滑块是结构与
texture
织构
structure and texture are reconstruction
结构和纹理是重建的
strategies if we move this slider over
策略 如果我们把这个滑块移到
to the structure side
到结构一侧
we're basically saying we don't care
我们基本上是在说我们不在乎
what's in the middle of the patch we are
我们在补丁中间的是什么
reconstructing
重建
we just want a smooth in painting a
我们只想画得流畅些
smooth gradient
平滑渐变
that works great with things like
这对像这样的事情很有效
overblown skies
乌云密布的天空
whereas the texture strategy attempts to
而纹理策略则试图
recover and creates detail
恢复并创建详细信息
this might be useful for things like
这可能对以下情况有用
skin or textured surfaces
蒙皮或纹理表面
i'll be honest i've never had a case
老实说 我从来没有接过案子
where going full texture was better than
去全质感的地方比
structure
结构
understand the texture mode attempts to
了解纹理模式尝试
recover detail from unclipped channels
从未剪辑的通道中恢复详细信息
but that has never yielded me any
但这从来没有给我带来过任何
results that i was satisfied with
我很满意的结果
therefore i either keep this at 0
因此 我要么将其保持在0
or lean a little bit to the left
或者稍微向左倾斜一点
i think zero is fine in this case
我认为在这种情况下零是可以的
now for bloom versus reconstruct
现在是开花与重建的对决
i've noticed that blooming works very
我注意到绽放的效果非常好
well when it comes to skies and the sun
当谈到天空和太阳的时候
for example
例如
however with objects that are
但是 对于符合以下条件的对象
illuminated by a bright light
被明亮的灯光照亮
i find that keeping to the right yells
我发现坚持正确会让人大喊大叫
better results
更好的结果
i'm going to keep that at 100
我会把它保持在100
reconstruct
重建
lastly
最后
gray or colorful details this one is
灰色或彩色细节这一张是
easy
易如反掌
i almost always keep the left of the
我几乎总是把左边的
slider
滑块
a portion of the capture we are trying
我们正在尝试捕获的一部分
to reconstruct almost never holds any
重建几乎从未持有过任何
meaningful color
有意义的颜色
as at least one channel was clipped at
因为至少有一个频道在
the sensor at the time of the capture
捕获时的传感器
that means that the color information is
这意味着颜色信息是
gone and there is no point in trying to
已经走了 没有必要去尝试
recover it i'll go 100 gray this time as
找回它 这一次我会变成100灰色
well
井
done the pink is gone
做完了 粉色就不见了
we have this
我们有这个
flatish white area
平坦的白色区域
but i think we can fix that
但我想我们可以解决这个问题
first i'll enable the color balance rgb
首先 我将启用色彩平衡RGB
i'll do the quickdom thing again and
我会再做一次快速的动作
just boost the global vibrance
只需提升全球活力
let's not get into the depths of color
让我们不要进入色彩的深处
balance rgb module just yet
平衡RGB模块
okay looks much more vibrant
好的 看起来更有活力了
right now we have this lovely warm sunny
现在我们有一个可爱的温暖的阳光
view
观
but the incoming light is very white it
但是入射的光是非常白的
is slightly uncanny and ruins the
有点不可思议 并毁掉了
imagine
想象一下
what we can do as artists
作为艺术家 我们能做些什么
we can do some close domain
我们可以做一些封闭的领域
modifications
修改
in short i'm taking out the brush the
简而言之 我是在拿出刷子
scarf and the beret and i'm going to
围巾和贝雷帽 我要
paint something on my photo
在我的照片上画点什么
i'm going to duplicate the color balance
我要复制颜色平衡
rgb module
RGB模块
and i'm going to create a new instance
我将创建一个新的实例
i'll reset it just in case
我会重新设置的 以防万一
and i'm going to ctrl and shift and
我要按住Ctrl键和Shift键
click it and drag it above filmic rgb
单击它并将其拖动到电影RGB上方
this means that we're not influencing
这意味着我们不会影响
filmic rgb module with this artistic
电影RGB模块 带有此艺术性
adjustment and we're working with closed
调整 我们正在与Closed合作
domain data also known as display
域数据也称为显示
repaired
修过
first of all let's do a quick parametric
首先 让我们做一个快速的参数
mask
遮罩
i'll enable the mask preview and i will
我将启用蒙版预览 我将
invert the mask
反转蒙版
grab the slider and walk it back
抓住滑块 然后走回去
until we've selected the over exposed
直到我们选择了过度曝光的
areas
区域
i'll do a bit of feathering
我会做一些羽化的动作
a bit of blurring
有点模糊
maybe a tiny bit more
也许再多一点
this back a little bit
这个后退了一点
yeah i think that is okay
好的 我想没问题
that will do the job
那会做好这项工作的
i can disable the mask preview
我可以禁用蒙版预览
and i'm going to go straight to the four
我要直接去四个
ways and
方法和方法
i'm going to change the hue
我要改一下色调
of the highlights gain
的亮点收益
i'm going to change it to something
我要把它改成别的东西
warm
温暖的
ish
伊什
now what i need to do is increase the
现在我需要做的是增加
chroma
色度
just a tiny tiny little bit
只有一点点一点点
let's not overdo it and turn it into
我们不要做过头了 把它变成
sepia
深褐色
just a little bit so it feels
只是一点点 所以感觉
warmer
变暖了
okay
好吧
again enable color assessment mode to
再次启用颜色评估模式以
help us judge
帮我们评断
okay that's a bit too orangey
好的 这有点太夸张了
okay i'm pretty happy with that i think
好的 我想我对此很满意
that did it
就是这样
i think we managed to salvage it
我想我们设法挽救了它
from an image that was about to be
从一幅即将成为
discarded to something that we can
被丢弃到我们能做的事情上
actually use
实际使用
i'm happy with the result
我对结果很满意
even though we only mainly touched a few
尽管我们主要只接触到了几个
modules
模块
so color balance rgb filmic rgb
所以色彩平衡RGB胶片RGB
exposure
暴露
color calibration
颜色校准
oh and perspective
哦 还有观点
and that's about it
仅此而已
in reality i would keep working on this
事实上 我会继续做这件事
image until i'm fully happy but for the
形象 直到我完全快乐 但对于
purposes of this video i think it's more
这个视频的目的我认为它不仅仅是
than acceptable
超出可接受范围
next time
下次
we'll be looking at an even more complex
我们将看到一个更复杂的
problem
问题
saturated colors in broken highlights
破碎高光中的饱和色
but that's going to be it for the part 2
但这将是第二部分
of the deep dive into filmic rgb
深入研究RGB电影
hope you learned something new today
希望你今天学到了新东西
i'll see you soon
我很快就会见到你
bye
再见
you
你